Today we're going to be discussing Magic, The Gathering, the card game.
The end phase is a part where, since it is my turn, I can decide I am done or finished.
Usually people just say they are done.
Now, this step, in and of itself, is a phase.
However, the only thing that you can do during this phase is play an instant.
For instance, we are going to tap this for two and a black and we're going to play an eye of lights ending which is a tribal instant elf.
Now, this says on the card, destroy target non-elf creature.
We are, for instance, going to destroy the zombie that gave us so much trouble during our combat with its regenerative abilities.
We're going to destroy the bone emitter.
We destroy him, and this is all during the end phase.
He goes to the graveyard.
Now, this zombie avatar, which was a three, three is now only a one, one because he only gets credit for one.
One zombie is now in play.
That being done during the end phase, as you said, when I play the instant during my end phase.
You must proclaim that it's during the end phase, and not for instance during your opponent's upkeep phase because when you are done and your going to do something you must vocalize this otherwise you can't do it.
That in turn begins the beginning of your opponent's upkeep phase.
Those are the phases of the game.